(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-25T21:03:35.913124",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
みんな！
Everyone!
今日は私のとっておきの3Dお披露目配信に来てくれて、ありがとうございます！
Thank you for coming to my 3D debut stream!
初見さん関係なく楽しめるように頑張っていくので、最後まで楽しんでいってね！
I'll make sure you can enjoy it even if you're new, so please enjoy it all the way to the end!
満点な人生も 秀才な解答もございません
Even a perfect life has no genius solutions.
有害な評論も 見え透いた同情も 聞きたくはないな
I don't want to hear harmful reviews or transparent sympathy.
壮観な表彰も 平凡な真っ当もございません
Even a grand expression has no ordinary truth.
暗転な将来も 傲慢な快晴も 見たくはないな
I don't want to see a gloomy future or arrogant optimism.
はいはい 俯いちゃって やーやーやん クラクラリ さまよって
Hey, hey, hanging my head so low, dizzy, wandering.
正答 失いちゃって わんわんわん だって 心は満たされない！
Can't quite find the solution, why is my heart never satisfied?
愛をちょだい 感情熱唱 メッメッメッメッ声枯らせ
Love me more and scream your lungs out with passionate feelings!
全然わかんない バッテン くらいつくせ
Haven't got a clue, bite down on the red marks.
心臓結晶 ラッッタッタッ踊りまえ
Churning blood runs through the pathways of your heart.
正解なんてバイバイ提唱 だーだーだーだーわおーん！
Here's my final answer - goodbye! (Awoo!)
満点な答案も 優秀な成功もございません
Even a perfect answer has no outstanding success.
後悔な人生も 停滞の殺戮も 見たくはないな
I don't want to see a life of regrets or stagnant murder.
毎回つまんいちゃって きゃんきゃんきゃん フラフラリ
Round and round, every round I'm wavering.
感嘆出来で
Can't feel a thing.
正答 無くなっちゃって わんわんわん 待って 出口も見当たらない？
Lost for good, wait, how'd I end up trapped with no one by my side?
愛をちょだい 感情熱唱 メッメッメッメッ声枯らせ
Love me more and scream your lungs out with passionate feelings!
全然止まんない バッテン 笑い倒せ
There's no end in sight, beat down the red while laughing.
心臓結晶 真っ赤ッカッ踊りまえ
Churning blood runs scarlet all throughout your heart.
正解なんて無い無い提唱 だーだーだーだーわおーん！
Here's my final answer - it's a lie! (Awoo!)
愛をちょだい 感情熱唱 メッメッメッメッ歌うたえ
Love me more and calling out these words to leave a scar.
全然染まんない がっつら抜けとうせ
Try to leave a mark, break through your swollen ego.
心鏡全勝 落書きはい上がれ
Crawling, falling to your knees, there's nothing in your heart.
正解なんて曖昧律しよ だーだーだーだー
I'll prove that the answer's undefined.
感情熱唱 メッメッメッメッ声枯らせ
Love me more and scream your lungs out with passionate feelings!
全然わかんない バッテン くらいつくせ
Haven't got a clue, bite down on all the red marks.
心臓結晶 ラッッタッタッ踊りまえ
Churning blood runs through the pathways of your heart.
正解なんてバイバイ推奨 だーだーだーだー
Here's my final answer - goodbye!
正解なんて無い無い提唱 だーだーだーだーわおーん！
Here's my final answer - it's a lie!
愛をちょだい 感情烈傷 メッメッメッメッ歌うたえ
Love me more and scream your lungs out with passionate feelings!
全然染まんない かっつら抜けとせ 心鏡全勝
Haven't got a clue, bite down on all the red marks.
落書きはい上がれ 正解なんて曖昧律証 だーだーだーだー
Churning blood runs through the pathways of your heart.
感情熱唱 メッメッメッメッ声枯らせ 全然わかんない バッテン くらいつくせ
Here's my final answer - goodbye!
心臓結晶 ラッッタッタッ踊りまえ 正解なんてバイバイ推奨 だーだーだーだー
Here's my final answer - it's a lie!
正解なんて無い無い提唱 だーだーだーだーだーだーだーだーわおーん！
Undefined!
はーい、みんな！
Ah, everyone!
こんこよ見えてますか？
Can you see Koyori?
ホロライブ6期生
Hololive Roku-kisei (6th Gen)...
博衣こよりだよー！
Hakui Koyori!
というわけで！
And so...
博衣こよりの3Dお披露目配信始まるよー！
Hakui Koyori's 3D debut stream has started!
お待たせー！
Sorry to keep you waiting!
まずは、えーデビューのときにだした歌ってみたの曲
First, for the cover song I released at my debut,
「ルンバ」を歌って踊ってみたのですが、
"LumLa," I tried singing and dancing to it,
どうだったかなあ！
how was it?!
え、なんとですねこちら、
And guess what, for this one,
え、サビは先生に振り付けていただいたんですけど、
the chorus choreography was done by a teacher,
サビ以外はですね、こよりが考えたダンスになってますー！
but the rest of the dance was thought up by Koyori!
よかったらあとでそんなことも考えながら、またもう1回見てみてくださいください！
If you'd like, please go back and watch it again while thinking about that!
いぇーい！
Yay!
うわ動いてるよみんな女子くん！
Whoa, you guys are moving, Joshikun!
いぇい、いぇい、いぇい、いぇい、いぇい！
Yay, yay, yay, yay, yay!
ということで、ちょっと待って、ちょっと息が切れちゃったんで、あの水飲んできていいですか？
So, wait, I ran out of breath a bit, so can I go drink some water?
ちょっとちょっと水取ってくるね！
I'll go grab some water real quick!
ふうー、これはもう水分補給しないとやってられないよねって、うんうんうん。
Phew, I really need to stay hydrated or I won't make it, yeah, yeah, yeah.
うめ！
Delicious!
今日も水が！
Today's water is...
うめー！
delicious!
あ、じょしくんも、じょしくんも飲みたい？飲みたい？
Ah, do you guys want to drink too? Do you want some?
せーのっ！
Ready, set!
はい、こよりの大好きなマヨネーズ、あの作ってもらいました！
So, my favorite, mayonnaise, they made it for me!
ああ、飲める飲める、飲める飲める、あむ。
Ah, drinkable, drinkable, mhm.
ふうー！よし、もうこれで、もうバッチリです。
Whew! Alright, with this, I'm all set.
もうね、もう疲れも完全に取れたので、
And now, my fatigue is completely gone,
ちょっとこの、こよりズラボも、見てもらおうと思います。
so I'd like you all to take a look at K's Labo.
あ、その前にですね大事なこと、
Ah, and before that, something important:
今日のこの3Dライブのハッシュタグ「博衣こより3D」をつけていっぱいスクショ撮って拡散してくださいね！
Please take lots of screenshots with today's 3D live hashtag #HakuiKoyori3D and share them!
Twitterでツイートよろしくお願いします！いぇーい！
Please tweet on Twitter! Yay!
それでは、じゃあちょっとまず、そうだ、みんな、心のこと気になってんじゃないかな。
Now then, first, wait, you guys are probably wondering about Kokoro.
こよと一緒に見て、こころも、うぃんうぃんうぃんうぃんうぃん、一緒に3Dになったんですよ！ロボこよってこころですね。
Together with Koyo, Kokoro became 3D too, wiiiiin! It's Robocoyori's Kokoro.
このロボこよって、持つことができるので、
Since you can hold this Robocoyori,
ちょっとここから出よっか。ねえ、ずっと入ってんのもね、やだもんね。
let's take it out of there. You know, staying in there all the time sucks, right?
よしこから出しちゃうよっ！
So let's take Kokoro out!
こころだよー！あ、ぱく、こころ、みんなよろしくね！ロボこよっての、こころだよ！
It's Kokoro! Ah, pak, Kokoro, everyone say hi! It's Robocoyori's Kokoro!
ちゃんとこよのねポッケからでてるんですよ、いい！
It's actually coming out of Koyo's pocket, how cute!
かわいいでしょう！いぇいいぇいいぇい、こころもなんかちょっと、さっきよりデカくなったような気が、ん、ん、ん、ん？
Ain't it cute?! Yay, yay, yay, Kokoro feels a bit bigger than before, huh, mhm?
ご本、ごほん、しますがい、それを置いといてさ、こころもこんな風になってるんですが、
Ahem, ahem, anyway, setting that aside, Kokoro turned out like this too, but...
あの、助手くんたちの姿もね、このこころと同じロボこようなんですよね。
You see, the Joshikun's forms are also Robocoyori, just like Kokoro.
で、ちょっと見分けがつかないなってことで、今回新たなデザインをですね、作っちゃったんです！
So, since it's hard to tell them apart, we created a brand new design this time!
じゃあちょっとこころ戻ってもらって、
So, Kokoro, go back in for a sec,
よいしょ。
heave-ho.
ではでは、そんな助手くんを今から大量生産していきたいと思います！
Now then, we're going to mass-produce those Joshikuns right now!
え、みんながね、いっぱい応援してくれているコメントやスーパーチャットの、え、力をエネルギーにして、なんとこのラボ動くんです！
With the energy from everyone's supportive comments and super chats, this lab actually moves!
ちょっと動かしてみっちゃおうかな！それでは、
Let's try moving it! Here we go:
動け！こよラボ！
Move, Koyo Lab!
動いたー！
It's moving!
見て、あ、もう、もうゲーミング助手くんが生まれちゃった！
Look, oh, a gaming Joshikun has just been born!
見てください、このように、え、助手くんがですね、スーパーチャットの、あの、原理で何？スーパーチャットの力を得て、大量生産されていくようになりました！かわいいー！
Look at this, Joshikuns are now being mass-produced using the power of Super Chats! So cute!
え、しかもね、この首輪がついているのが、助手くんのデザインというふうにね、あの、新しくなりましたので、みんな首輪をプレゼントだよ！いぇーい！
And what's more, having this collar is the new design for Joshikun, so everyone gets a collar present! Yay!
あとですね、さらにこのラボを花火まで出すことができます！これ！
Also, we can even shoot off fireworks from this lab! This!
これもみんなの応援のおかげで、ぱーん、ぱーん、出てますのでありがとうございます！
Thanks to everyone's cheers, bang, bang, they're coming out, thank you!
あ、しかも今この花火は飛ぶんですね。なんとTwitterのトレンド1位になったということで、みんないっぱいツイートもありがとう！お祝いの花火じゃあ、こよや！
And what's more, these fireworks fly! Since we reached #1 on Twitter trends, thank you for all the tweets! Fireworks to celebrate, Koyo-ya!
ていうわけで、まあまだまだちょっと見せたいところいっぱいあるんですが、
That being said, there's still a lot more I want to show you,
今日はですね、みんなに楽しんでいただけるように、コーナーを準備しているので、まずはずっと目のコーナーに行っちゃおうと思います！
but today, to make sure everyone has fun, we've prepared some corners, so let's head right into the first corner!
1つ目のコーナーは、
The first corner is...
こちら！ゲストからの指令に答えろ！
Here! "Answer the instructions from the guest!"
ということで、こよは研究者なので、え、ゲストからいろんな指令に答えていろんなポーズ...
So, since Koyori is a researcher, answering various instructions from guests and doing various poses...
す…することができる
I-I can...
できれば…
If possible...
なんかすごいスクリーンがうむこと、ん？スクリーンを生むことができるのではないか
like, create an amazing screen— wait, can I generate a screen?
という検証を行っていこうと思います。
I'm going to run that verification test!
そしてですね、この検証に成功すると、
And if this verification test is successful,
なんとこのコヨラボのとある機能をお披露目することができるらしいですよの！
apparently we get to unveil a certain feature here at Koyolabo!
気になるよね！
You're curious, right?
では、さっそくゲストをお呼びしちゃおうと思います。
So, let's go ahead and invite our guests!
まずは…ホロックスのみんなー！
First up... everyone from Holox!
聞こえるかな？
Can you hear me?
あー！イエーイ！みんな見てるー！
Ah! Yay! Is everyone watching?!
いや検証じゃなーい！わー！ありがとー！
No, that's not the test! Yay! Thank you!
めっちゃかわいい！
So cute!
花火を、花火を口から打って…花火を…一緒にコード長崎音頭を踊ろうね！
Shoot fireworks out of your mouth... fireworks... let's dance the Code Nagasaki Ondo together!
それじゃあラプラスちゃんから、あの名前の自己紹介をお願いします！
Next, Laplus-chan, please give us your name and self-introduction!
角目星、我がハイダーラプラスダークネスです！えい！
Horns and stars, I am Laplus Darknesss! Ei!
はい、またかね、たかねるいであー！えい！
Yes, Takane Lui here! Ei!
はい、坂又クロでー！えいど！
Yes, Sakamata Chloe here! Eidou!
はい、風見いろはでござる！ござるー！ってことで
Yes, Kazama Iroha here, deezaru! Deezaru! So—
ホロックスの4人に来てもらいましたー！
We have all four members of Holox here with us!
いやい…やったー！やったー！
Yay! Yay!
なんかしてほしいポーズとかある？
Are there any poses you'd like them to do?
たかねるいが大好きなやつやってもらっていいですか？
Takane Lui, can you do your absolute favorite thing?
え、なになに？
Eh, what what?
はい！はい！やったー！やったーのポーズしてほしいな！
Yes! Yes! Do the "Yay! Yay!" pose!
オッケーオッケー、じゃあそれにふりを付けるか、オープニングにね。あ、そうそうそうそうそうやってほしい！
Okay okay, then let's add some choreography to that for the opening. Ah, yes, yes, please do it like that!
はい！はい！はい！はい！やったー！やったー！わーかわいい！ねえ、これ見に来たまであるぞ！
Yay! Yay! Yay! Yay! Yay! Yay! So cute! Seriously, I came just to see this!
パラパラ踊ってるところがあるんだけど…
There's a part where they dance parapara, but...
なんかチャームポイントがあるとか、なんとか？そうなんだけどさ！チャームポイントどこだ？
They said there's some charm point or something? That's right! Where's your charm point?
え、ルイ姉さすがだね！今まで見せられなかったチャームポイントなんだけど…
Eh, Lui-nee is amazing! It's a charm point we haven't been able to show until now...
これ見て！
Look at this!
え、ろ、え、そこじゃないよ、もっと見せろよ、あな…穴とかいいんですか、うちの…穴は穴やろ！
Eh, ro-, eh, not there, show more, ho-... are holes okay for our... A hole's a hole!
穴というか、穴をとらえての問題だからな！あ、穴やろ！
It's a matter of capturing the hole! Ah, a hole is a hole!
つけ取りでの問題だからな！穴やろ！つけ取りでの問題だからな！
It's about taking it off! A hole is a hole! It's about detaching it!
え、めっちゃエッチ！最高やん！ねえ！尻尾出てる、可愛い！可愛い！めっちゃチャームポイントもふもふ！うわ恥ずかしい！
Eh, so lewd! Awesome! Hey! Tail's sticking out, cute! Cute! Super fluffy charm point! Wow, how embarrassing!
ちょっと、ちょっと待って、じゃあちょっと坂下やってほしいなあるんだよね。
Wait, wait a minute, so I'd like Sakamata to do something too.
え、オッケーオッケー、何々？まず手を後ろに組みます。はい。
Eh, okay okay, what is it? First, put your hands behind your back. Yes.
座ります。こまがいな、座る、はい。
Sit down. Komagaina, sit, yes.
顔、顔ごまらして、困ま、え？何これ？
Make a troubled face, trou-, eh? What is this?
はいはい、できあがり！はい、これ誘拐されたポーズ！
Yes yes, done! Yes, this is the kidnapped pose!
お前のせいで！すいません、やめろ！閉めときます！エロライバルずんだ！ほら！
Because of you! Sorry, stop it! I'll close it! Lewd rival Zunda! Look!
エロップとかないわけ？ないわよ！ねえ、さすがクロターんだね！
You don't have lewd ropes or anything? Of course not! Right, as expected of Kuro-tarin!
え、いろはちゃん何かある？ね、風間やっぱこよちゃんのね、ピコーンってなる耳みたいだから、めっチャラってなったりしないかな？ピコーンてなったりしないかな？
Eh, Iroha-chan, do you have anything? Hey, Kazama, since you like Koyori's ears that go "picoon!", wouldn't it be super cute if they did that too?
できたの！もっとピコーンてなるのあるんだよ！
You can do it! There's an even more "picoon!" version!
できるんですか？れちゃった！パーハー、ピコーン！ピコーンしとる！え、どこ、どこで吸えますか？
Can you do it? It came out! Paha, picoon! It's picooning! Eh, where, where can I inhale this?
こよにの頭で吸えるなら、吸うなら、みんないろんなポーズしてさせてくれてありがとう！もうめっちゃかわいい！ありがとう、このあとも頑張るね！
If I can inhale on Koyoni's head, if I inhale, thank you everyone for posing for me! So cute! Thank you, I'll keep doing my best!
がんばるぞ！ありがとうございます！とことん、なんか受け取った最後、ファンの人が「ありがとうございます」って言って受け取っていた気がするけど…
I'll do my best! Thank you very much! In the end, I feel like fans received it saying "Thank you very much," but...
ホロックスのみんなに来てもらいましたー！いろんなポーズさせてもらえたね！ね、さすがか、さすがやっぱり、こういうの、仲間よくわかっておる。
We had everyone from Holox come over! You let us do all sorts of poses! Right, as expected of our comrades, they really understand this stuff.
では、続きまして…、え、仲間ではなく、先輩からいろんなことを聞いたら、さらにいいポーズができちゃうんじゃないかってことで、この方々をお呼びしようと思います！
Now, moving on... uh, not comrades, but if we ask our seniors about various things, we might be able to pull off even better poses! With that in mind, let's invite these guests!
カナリアのお二人ー！イエーイ！先輩から年上の…あっ、止めちゃった！あー、ごめんごめん！
The Canary duo! Yay! From our seniors, older... Ah, I stopped it! Ah, sorry sorry!
よし！ じゃあ先輩たちのポーズ指定に
All right! So, responding to our seniors' pose requests...
外でポーズ取ってくれるということで！
we're going to take some cute idol poses outside!
ぜひ！なんでもやってくれるってほんと？ほんとに？
Wait, really? They'll do anything?
あ、そうです！先輩の言うことだったらなんでもします！
Oh, I see! If it's what our seniors say, I'll do anything!
あ、なんでも！ポーズする方なんでもやってくれるってなんでも？やったよ！
Oh, anything? Anyone who poses can do anything? Oh, wow.
そっか。じゃあちょっとアイドルっぽいポーズをまずはね、そうですね。
Well, then, let's have them strike an idol pose first.
ぜひねちょっと先輩から、ぜひね、ぜひね。
First, let's ask our senior to do it. Please!
じゃあ、あの、僕がよくやる大好きなアイドルポーズなんですけど、
Then, an idol pose that I love to do...
両手を前に伸ばして、両手？そうそうそう、でちょっと、
両手を前に伸ばして、両手を... そうそうそうそう！
片足をぴって上げて、首を固定みたいな感じの。
And then, put one leg up and strike a neck-lock-like pose.
ちょっとこれ、あ、あ、かわいい！バランス感覚、かわいい！
Wait, that's cute! Great balance! Koyori is cute!
ちょっともうちょっと引いたのも見たいな！足、足のも見たいじゃん。
Wait, I want to see you pull back a bit more. I want to see your feet!
足も見たい！足も、ぐってやったほうが、あ、いいね、いいね！かわいい、かわいい！
I want to see your feet. Do it with your feet! Oh, nice, nice!
だけど、もっと引いてからもお願いします！もっと引いてからも、ちょっと長いな。
Wait, but please pull back a bit more! Pull back more!
あ、バランス感覚が！あ、素晴らしい、素晴らしい！あーかわいい！
Oh, that balance is great, wonderful, wonderful! Aah, cute!
いや、そうか。これ、これがアイドルフってことですね！
Wait, so that's what an idol is!
これがアイドルだな。そうだな！
That's an idol! Right.
え、じゃあ、私もいいかな？はい。うしろ。
Well then, is it my turn? Yes, let's do it.
あの、やっぱりあの、アイドル、我々アイドルの先輩として、あの、やってきた伝統のね、ものがあるんでちょっとやってもらいたいんですけど。
As idols, as seniors to idols, there's a traditional pose we've done, so I'd love you to do that.
やりたいです。後ろを向いてもらって、数歩歩いてくるっと振り向いて、なんか一言言って！
First, turn around, walk a few steps, turn back around, and say a line!
え、一言？あ、ちょっと待って！うーん、うーん。
A line? Wait, wait! Um...
アイしてるぞ！
I'm dumping you!
いや、待って、一言が難しい！難しい！難しい！難しい！ちょっと待って、待って待って待って。
Wait, a line is hard! Hard, hard, hard! Wait, wait, wait, wait!
そう、こういうのめっちゃかわいいじゃん！後ろもしっかり見てもらいたいからさ。
That's cute, though! Turn around and look properly, because we want to see you!
そう、そうだな、そうだな。もう全身くまなく見てほしいよね。
That's right, that's right. You want to see your whole body.
しかも進行わかっていらっしゃる。
Especially since you know the progression!
さあ、じゃあ、あのカメラをちょっと下に置いて、
Now, let's place the camera lower...
この下に転んじゃった僕たちに対して「大丈夫？」ってこう近づいてくれる...
And come close, saying "Are you okay?" to us who tripped down there!
あーいいですね！やってほしいです。
Oh, I see! I want you to do that!
転んじゃったの？
You tripped?
大丈夫？うわ、これめっちゃいい！どうしよう、かわいい！素晴らしい！
Are you okay? Wow, this is so good! It's so cute!
ありがとー！天国まで行きました。ありがとう！
Thank you, you went all the way to heaven! Thank you!
いや、ちょっと飛んでってくだいよ。天国行くの早すぎんだわ！
Hey, fly away! Heaven is just around the corner!
魂も飛んでったわ！楽しかった！最高だな。
My soul also flew away! But that was great.
なんかさ、まださ、もう1個見せてくれるって聞いたんですけど。
Wait, I heard there's one more you can show us. Is that true?
なんかそうなんです。ちょっとお二人目に何かいらっしゃるらしいて。
Something? We hear something is going to happen to both of us!
そうなんです、お二人だったらちょっと料理してくれるんじゃないかなってちょっとつけてきますね、こより。
If it's the two of you, maybe you can cook something for us? Let's check it out, Koyori!
ちょっと、なんだろうね。いったい何が。料理してくじんだね！
Wait, what could it be? Cooking for us?
料理してくじます？え！メガネの要素が来たぞ！うわ！すげえ、まじか！おもろい！
Cooking for us? Oh! Glasses mode has arrived! That's amazing! Funny!
え、じゃあちょ、はいはいはいはい！じゃ、先にちょっと年上からやってもいいですか？はい、オッケーオッケーです！
Wait, wait! Let me do it from the year before! Is that okay? Okay, perfect!
やっぱ、これはね、あの、みんな求めてると思うので、まずじゃあちょっと寝転がってもらっていいですか？寝転がって、はい！
Well, this is something everyone wants, so first, please lie down!
寝転がってもらって、上からちょっと押し倒してる感じでやってほしいな！押し倒してるとこなのかな、それ。
Lie down, and from above, push us down like this!
あ、ここ長くて、私アイドルなんだよってちょっと言ってほしいの。うわー！こより、アイドルなんだよ！
Wait, I'm an idol! Let me say that. Koyori, I'm an idol, you know!
あー！ありがとうございます！
Aah, thank you!
ちょっと待って、これアイドルですか？これ、アイドルですか？
Wait, is this really an idol? Is this really an idol?
アイドルだって必要なんだよ！こより、アイドルだから！そうだ、そうだ！
It's necessary for idols, Koyori! Idols need this!
だからアイドルだからね、アイドルなんだよって言ったからアイドルですね。
Because we're idols, right? You said we're idols, so it's idol!
じゃあちょっと、アイドルのシチュエーションと言ったらもう僕にお任せ、この状態で、え、またカメラは下からのアングルになっていただき、
So, when it comes to the idol situation, leave it to me. In that state, please set the camera to a low angle.
下からのアングル、大好きよ！
Oh, I love that!
あの、踏んでください！
Please step on us!
あ、ちょっと、呆然とした感じで踏んでほしいです！
Wait, I want you to step on us in a somewhat dazed way!
あ、見えた、見えた！
Oh, I can see it! I can see it!
下から、下からって、下からばっかりで！もう、変態なんだから！
From below, from below, always from below! Hey, you pervert!
ほら、ほら、ほら、ほら！
Look, look, look!
え、待ってこれアイドル？ねえ、アイドルだったこれ？
Wait, is this an idol? Hey, is this really an idol?
アイドルだろ！なんだ、やってきたんだ先輩たちも！
It's an idol, though! Our seniors came all this way!
全く！いや、アーカイブ残るぞ、本当か？
Definitely! Yes, archives are available, really?
じゃあちょっとあの、最後にもう一個私のもいいですか？
Then, can we have one last one, please?
あ、どうぞどうぞ！あの、近づいてもらって、ちょっと壁ドンやってもらっていいですか？
Oh, sure! Come closer and do it along the wall, please!
わかりました。
Understood.
これがアイドルか？ちょっと心配になってきたから！かなたのとかなた、またか！ありがとう！ありがとうございます！
This might be an idol... I'm starting to get nervous! Canaria and Kanata, again?! Thank you!
大好きだぞ！ありがとうございました！
I love it! Thank you very much!
ってことで、ちょっと不安になったんで切りました。
So, I got a bit nervous, so I stopped.
これ大丈夫だったかな？これ、こよりの、しじま ちこよりになってるだけで、こよりに問題はないのでYouTubeさんよろしくお願いします！はは！
Was that alright? Well, this is just Shijimachi Koyori's stream, but since there's no problem for Koyori, YouTube-san, please be nice to us!
それでは、続きまして、ちょっともっとやばい気がするんですけど、
And then, following that, I feel like something even more dangerous is coming...
頭がピンクっぽい皆さんをお呼びしたいと思います！
I'd like to invite all the pink-headed people here!
頭ピンクっぽい皆さん〜！
All you pink-headed folks~!
こんまっする！こんまっする！
Kon-muscle! Kon-muscle!
頭？あれ？髪の色じゃなく、ちょっと身長、ほら？
Head? Huh? Not hair color, but height, see?
男子禁制なんですけど、いいんですか？ここに。
It's strictly for girls, is it okay for you to be here?
あ、なんでいるの？
Ah, why are you here?
頭の中がピンク色かなって。
I figured your heads were full of pink.
いろんなピンクの格好させてくれるんじゃないかなって。
Hoping you'd let us wear all kinds of pink outfits.
あ、じゃあお名前よろしくお願いします！
Ah, please state your names!
えー、エリートみか、頭がピンク色の髪型…サクラ・ウミコね？
Uh, Elite Miko, with pink hair... Sakura Umiko, right?
えー、頭がピンクすぎてちょっと濃いピンク、いや、赤、赤までいきました！
Uh, her head is way too pink, a bit dark pink... no, red, it went all the way to red!
男子禁制なんです！
It's strictly for girls!
はい、こんまっする！
Yes, kon-muscle!
えー、ちょっと髪の毛もピンクを通り越して、真っ白というか銀髪になってしまった。
Um, her hair went past pink and turned pure white, or rather, silver.
ま、中身はね、でも誰よりもピンクだと噂されている。
Well, inside, she's rumored to be pinker than anyone else.
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you very much!
ちょっと今日はもうこよりのアイドル人生を終わらせに来たから。やめてやめて！
Today I came to end Koyori's idol career. Stop, stop!
やっぱね、船長ね、ちょっと一番ね、ずーっとずっと思ってたことがあって。こよりお前の着ているシャツ、それ短いよね、どう考えてもね。
As I thought, Captain, there's something I've been wondering about for a long time. Koyori, the shirt you're wearing is short, no matter how you look at it.
おっぱいでお腹が盛り上がっちゃってさ、
Your belly is pushed up by your boobs,
シャツがめくり上がっちゃって、
making the shirt roll up,
ちょっと3Dだから覗き込めるのかなって。覗いちゃえ！
I wonder if I can peek since it's 3D. Let's take a peek!
でもこれ、このさ、上着ちょっと邪魔じゃないか？邪魔だな。
Wait, but isn't this jacket in the way? It's in the way.
確かに、こよりの羽織邪魔だな。抜け出せばただのこよりになっちゃう。
True, Koyori's haori is in the way. If she takes it off, she'll just be regular Koyori.
え？抜け出したいの？抜け出したい！
Huh? You want to slip out? I want to slip out!
今までこより脱いだことないから抜けたかったんだよね今まで。だから抜けるわけ！
I've never taken it off before, I've always wanted to. That's why I can take it off!
大丈夫？ちょっと見せてごらんなさい、脇を。脇を！
Are you okay? Show me your armpits a bit. Your armpits!
桃色だよこの脇。これが脇開いたってことです。
It's peach-colored, this armpit. This means opening the armpits.
ちょっと、あの、ほてっちゃってるかもしれないですね、今3Dを披露めで。
Maybe I'm getting flushed, showing off in 3D now.
ほてっててってことは、そのさ、シャツの中も、もしや、ほてって、
If I'm flushed, does that mean inside the shirt, maybe it's flushed...
行ける範囲？めくったほうがいいか。そい方がいいか！
Is this a manageable range? Better flip it up. Better do that!
わあ、なんだこりゃ。ちょっと、待って、
Whoa, what is this? Wait, wait,
ま、ちょっと、大丈夫か？ね、大丈夫か？
hang in there. Are you okay? Right, are you okay?
ジャンプしたらめくれないから。ジャンプしろ、ジャンプしろ！
If you jump, it won't flip up. Jump! Jump!
いろんな件、貼り付いてるのこれ。めくれないの。
Quite a lot of things are stuck to this. Can't flip it.
あれじゃない？あのブリッジしろよ。ブリッジ！
Isn't that? Do a bridge! Bridge!
で、人生の終わりといえばブリッジまであるよ。こよりのできるか、ブリッジ。
Speaking of the end of life, there's even a bridge. Can Koyori do a bridge?
お腹が見えてる！お腹が見えてるよ！この暴れないんじゃ暴れが、あ、そう、写ってる、お腹が見えるよ！
Her belly is showing! Her belly is showing! This wildness... ah, yeah, it's captured, you can see her belly!
なんかあるぜこれ、なんかある！なんかあるじゃん、これ、二つ見える。あるだろ！
There's something here, there's something! There are two things visible, aren't there?
上半身もいいけど、ちょっと下半身もよくないすか？この足。
Upper body is good, but isn't lower body good too? These legs.
足、タイツ履いてるでしょ？足が黒くなって、なんか濃く、あ、なんかヒールがすごい。あ、いいね、なんか回すように。
Legs, you're wearing tights, right? Legs are black, looking dark, ah, heels are amazing. Ah, nice, spinning around.
デニール気になるな。え、デニールちょっとよく見たいな。
I'm curious about the denier. I want to see the denier closer.
もっとよく見たいな。もっとちょっと、もっとちょっとゆっくり。
I want to see it better. A bit more, a bit more slowly.
おお、なんか、いやらしいかわいい！いやらしいハイヒール。
Oh, kind of indecent and cute! Indecent high heels.
このスカートが濃くなっていく。これ影がちょっと、エロいですね。
This skirt is getting darker. The shadows are a bit lewd.
自覚、自覚している？自覚いいね。このこよりは、頭がピンクやからな。
Self-awareness, are you aware? Self-awareness is good. This Koyori's head is pink after all.
いやいやいや、ピンクなのは髪型だけですよ！いよいよでも頭ピンク組ですもんね。求めでたんですよね、これを。
No, no, only the hairstyle is pink! Finally, we're the pink head group. You've been seeking this, haven't you?
あ、そう、そうなんです、皆さんだから。私たちにさ、ポーズ指示させて本当は自分でやりたいピンクのポーズがあるんだろ？え？あるんじゃない？
Ah, yes, exactly, because you guys are... making us pose, but you actually have a pink pose you want to do yourself, right? Huh? Isn't there?
エッチいんだろ？
Is it lewd?
エッチ、なんか...背中を見せるのや
Lewd... like showing your back.
え、そこでさ、そっからさ、よく...
Um, right there, and then, often...
あの、手をさ、下に地面につける、足をまっすぐしてさ、もう...美脚をアピールするポーズ
Um, you put your hands down on the ground, keep your legs straight, and... a pose that shows off your beautiful legs.
マリンさんがよくやるやつや！
That's the one Marine-san always does!
こういう...こういうこと！
Like this... like this!
あら かわいい！
Aww, cute!
しっぽいいいね！
Nice tail!
しっぽくないな
Wait, it's not a tail.
こんなポーズ...
Such a pose...
これより思いつかないです、やっぱ先輩たちはピンクだな！
I can't top that! As expected, our seniors are all pink!
やいやいやいやい、こっち側なのかな？みなさん後輩よ！
Wait, wait, wait, is it this side? You guys are my juniors!
いや、これからもぜひあのピンクな...色々に伝授していただければと思っております、先輩方に
Well, I hope you seniors will continue to pass down various pink knowledge to me!
任せなさいよ！任せなさい！
Leave it to us! Leave it to us!
いや、ありがとうございます！色んな格好もさせていただき、脱がせてもいただきまして...
Thank you so much! I got to wear various outfits and even had them stripped off...
ありがとうございます！ひろめ、頑張ってね！
Thank you! Hiro-me, do your best!
ありがとうございます！がんばります！
Thank you! I'll do my best!
というわけで、え、頭ピンク組の皆さんから、ちょっとミイグルミを剥がされてしまいました！
And so, my mini-plushies were stripped away by the pink-haired members!
さぁ皆さん、えっと、ゲストの皆さんによっていろんなポーズしたわけですけど、少しはばっちり撮れたかな？撮れた？
Now everyone, we did various poses requested by our guests, but I wonder if we got some great shots? Did we?
ではでは、この検証は...成功ということで！
Well then, let's call this verification a success!
え、最初にお話ししてました、このラボの、とある機能をお披露目したいと...思います！
Um, as I mentioned at the start, I'd like to unveil a certain feature of this lab!
それでは機能のお披露目と、ともに、二曲続けて曲を歌って踊っちゃおうと思うので、お聞きください！どうぞ！
So along with unveiling the feature, I'll be singing and dancing to two songs in a row, so please enjoy! Here we go!
私のこと知ってますか？
Do you know who I am?
可愛く見えてますか？
Do I look cute?
私の歌どうだろうな
What do you think of my singing?
うまく歌えてますか？
Am I singing well?
衣装だとかメイクだとか
My costume and makeup,
可愛く見えてますか？
Do I look cute wearing them?
振付とかファンサとかも
My dancing and fanservice too,
喜んでもらえますか？
Do they make you happy?
手は冷たくなって
My hands are getting cold
足は震える
And my legs are shaking,
それでも戦いたい
Even so, I still want to fight
アイドルだから
Because I'm an idol
バカにする奴は嫌いだ
I hate people who make fun of me
見下されるのも嫌いだ
I hate being looked down on too
“アイドルなんか”という言葉を 見てもいないくせに言うな
Don't say words like "idols are nothing" when you haven't even seen them!
頑張りを当然と言うな
Don't take my hard work for granted
イメージとか強制するな
Don't force an image on me
“アイドルなんか”という言葉は この世で一番大嫌いだ
And words like "idols are nothing" are the one thing I hate the most in this world!
プライベート見えないから
Because you can't see my private life
分からないと思います
I don't think you'd know
性格とか悪い方です
My personality is actually pretty bad
騙しちゃってますか？
Did I manage to fool you?
でも本気です本気なんです
But it's the truth, I'm being serious
ありのままの私を
Please accept the real me
好きになって推して下さい
Love me and support me
それってワガママですか？
Is that a selfish thing to ask?
きっと可愛くない
I'm sure I'm not cute
全部分かってる
I already knew it all
それでも好かれたい
Even so, I still want to be liked
アイドルだから
Because I'm an idol
皮肉言う奴は嫌いだ
I hate people who say sarcastic things
言い訳ばかりも嫌いだ
I hate people who keep making excuses too
“こんなもんか”という言葉を 軽々しく口にするな
And words like "is that all?" don't just say them so lightly!
勝手に限界決めるな
Don't just set limits on me
笑い者に何てするな
Don't make a fool out of me
“アイドルなんか”という言葉は この世で一番大嫌いだ
And words like "idols are nothing" are the one thing I hate the most in this world!
向かい風を切り裂け
Cutting through the headwinds
誇り高きアイドル
A proud idol
(目指そうぜ)
(Let's aim for it)
応援がなければ 活動できない
Without all the support, I can't do any work
好きな事ばかりじゃ 生きてはいけない
I can't live my life by doing only what I like
元気あげるはずが もらってばかりだし
Supposed to give you energy, but I just keep receiving
恩返しできる日まで 待ってて
Until the day I can repay you, wait for me!
初めて推しって呼べる存在に出逢えた
I finally met someone I could call my oshi
こよちゃんに出逢ってから人生が変わった
Ever since I met Koyori, my life changed
コヨリウムがないとこよは生きていけない
Without Koyolium, Koyo cannot survive
助手くんとこよちゃんとならなんだってできる
With Assistant-kun and Koyo, I can do anything
歓声が減っても 飽きられちゃっても
Even when cheers fade, even when people get bored
それでも笑っていたい アイドルだから
I still want to keep smiling, because I'm an idol
熱いファンの愛があって
With the love of passionate fans,
スタッフさんの愛があって
With the love of the staff,
いつも家族の愛があって 生きてる
And always my family's love, I live on
“アイドル”
As an idol
バカにする奴は嫌いだ 見下されるのも嫌いだ
I hate those who mock me, and those who look down on me
“アイドルなんか”という言葉を 見てもいないくせに言うな
Don't say words like "just an idol" without even watching!
頑張りを当然と言うな
Don't take my hard work for granted
イメージとか強制するな
Don't force an image upon me
“アイドルなんか”という言葉はこの世で一番大嫌いだ
Words like "just an idol" are what I hate most in this world!
裾が濡れたなら 乾くの待てばいい
If your hem got wet, you can just wait for it to dry
水音をたてて跳ねた
Splashing water and jumping up
きみが教えてくれたんだ
You taught me that,
もう怖くない
I'm no longer scared
握っていていてくれたこの手を離さなきゃだめだ
I have to let go of this hand you were holding for me
ひとりでもゆくよ 例え辛くても
I will go even if I'm alone, even if it's painful
みんなで見た夢は 必ず持ってくよ
The dream we saw together, I'll definitely take with me
みんなとがいいな みんなとがよかった
I wish I could be with everyone, I'm glad I was with everyone
でも目覚めた朝 誰も居ないんだね
But on the morning I woke up, no one was there
もう振り返っても 誰の影もない
Even if I look back now, there is no one's shadow
水たまりだけが光った
Only a puddle was shining
生きてくことはそれは立ち向かっていくこと
To live is to face forward and keep going
それがわかったなら 後は踏み出す勇気だけ
Once you know that, all that's left is courage to take a step
どこまでもゆくよ ここで知ったこと
I will go anywhere, with what I learned here
幸せという夢を叶えてみせるよ
I'll make the dream called happiness come true
みんなと離れても どんなに遠くなっても
Even if I'm separated from everyone, no matter how far I go
新しい朝に この僕は生きるよ
In the new morning, I will live on
ひとりでもゆくよ
I'll go alone,
死にたくなくても
even if I don't want to die.
声が聞こえるよ
I can hear a voice,
死ではいけないと
saying I must not die.
例え辛くても
Even if it's painful,
闇に閉ざされても
even if I'm shut in darkness,
心の奥には
deep in my heart
明かりが灯ってるよ
a light is lit.
巡って流れて
Revolving and flowing,
時は移ろいだ
time has shifted.
もう何があったか
I can't remember
思い出せないけど
what happened anymore, but
目を閉じてみれば
if I close my eyes,
みんなの笑い声
everyone's laughter...
なぜかそれが今
For some reason,
一番の宝物
that is now my most precious treasure.
ということで、
And so,
誇り高きアイドルの
the proud idol's
「一番の宝物」二曲続けて
"Ichiban no Takaramono" songs,
お聴きいただきました！
we listened to two in a row!
どうだったかな？
How was it?
えーみんな誇り高きアイドルの前に
Everyone, before the proud idol,
こよラボがバーンってなって
Koyolab became bam
バーンってなったの、見てくれた？
and bam, did you see it?
すごいでしょう！
Isn't it amazing!
あのラボはですね、なんと
That lab, you see,
ステージ転換をすることによって
by performing a stage change,
ライブステージに
can become
なることができるんです！すっごい！
a live stage! Amazing!
えーこよのね、あのライブステージで
Um, for my live stage,
ちょっとこよのあの泥臭い
I wanted to sing that gritty
アイドル感を歌いたいなと思って
idol feel of mine,
誇り高きアイドル、そしてあの
Proud Idol, and then
歌えるなら歌いたいなってなって
thinking if I could sing it, I wanted to,
大好きなね、エンジェルビーツの
and I got to sing Angel Beats'
一番の宝物歌わせていただきました！
"Ichiban no Takaramono" which I love so much!
さてさて、続いてなんですけど
Now then, moving on,
こよ、あのデビューした時から
ever since my debut, Koyori,
この曲を歌いたいけど、勇気が持てたら歌うって言ってる曲が1曲ずっとあったと思うんですよ。
there has always been one song I wanted to sing.
で、その曲を歌いたいなって思うんですが、
And I think I want to sing that song,
まだちょっと、3Dになっても自信が持ちきれないんです。
even in 3D I still lack confidence.
なので、あるチャレンジに成功することができたら、
So if I can succeed in a certain challenge,
アイドルとして一歩成長できるんじゃないかって思って、それで、ちょっとチャレンジしようと思うんだけど、
I thought I could grow as an idol, so I'll try it.
みんな応援してくれるかな？いい？いい？
Will everyone cheer me on? Is that okay?
いいかな？じゃあこよ頑張るね！
Is that okay? Then Koyori will do her best!
挑戦、見届けてください！では挑戦するところに行くよー！
Please watch over my challenge! Off I go!
えー飛行機に乗って、着陸！
Taking a plane, and landing!
ということで、サバンナに帰ってきました！
And so, I've returned to the savannah!
なんかおる、なんかおるな！
There's someone, there's someone here!
実家であるこよの実家、
My parental home, Koyori's parental home...
こんばんは！帰ってきましたー！
Good evening! I'm back!
ここではこのコーナーをやろうと思います。
We're going to do this corner here.
今夜のアイドルチャレンジ！
Tonight's Idol Challenge!
ちょっと……なんか遠くにちょこちょこいる動物がちょっと気になるんですけども（笑）
Um... I'm a bit curious about those animals scurrying around in the distance.
それではですね、あのアイドルというものは
Well then, as for idols,
いつでも体を張らなければいけない生き物だと、こよりは、あの、知っております。
I know they are creatures who must always put their bodies on the line.
なので、このサバンナでいくつかのチャレンジで体を張っていこうと思います。
That's why I'm going to put my body on the line with a few challenges here in the savanna.
で、今から3つチャレンジをするんですけれども、その中の1つでも成功することができたら、
So, I'll be doing three challenges starting now, and if I succeed in even one of them...
アイドルとしてレベルアップできたよ、ということにしまして……
it'll mean I've leveled up as an idol...
えーさっき言ってた曲を歌いたいなと思います。
Uh, I'd like to sing the song I mentioned earlier.
っていうのをこよが考えてたんですけど……
That's what I had in mind...
なんかい、なんかあのスタッフさんが一個ちょっと要素を増やしてたんですよ。
but somehow, the staff added one more element to it.
なんか、あの、さっき言ってたやつ出してもらっていいですか？
Um, could you show the one I mentioned earlier?
ねぇなんか出ちゃったんですけど！
Hey, something popped up!
あの、なぜかですね、このサバンナ、あの、魔術がかけられておりまして……
Somehow, for some reason, this savanna has had magic cast on it...
え、なんとチャレンジに失敗すると、
Uh, apparently if I fail the challenge,
この人間の姿のこよってから、野生に帰ってしまうらしいですよ？
I'll revert from my human form back to a wild animal?!
え、つ、え、どういうこと？え、まだ動きはないのかな？
Eh, wait, what do you mean? Eh, is it not moving yet?
う、あっ、あっ、うわぁぁぁぁぁぁぁぁぁぁぁぁぁ！
U-ah, ah, uwaaaaaaaaaah!
ちょっと吠えたくなったわ！ちょっと吠えたくなったじゃん！
I felt like howling! You made me feel like howling!
い、いままだまだ失敗しないから、はっ、はっ、はっ、戻れた、戻れた！よかった、よかった、よかった！
W-wait, I haven't failed yet, ha, ha, ha, I'm back, I'm back! Thank goodness, thank goodness!
えーというわけで、じゃあこのね、野生に帰ったらちょっとこよーりそのままサバンナに置いてけぼりになっちゃう可能性もあるんで、
So, if I revert to being wild, Koyori might be left behind in the savanna just like that,
成功できるように頑張っていこうと思います！
so I'll do my best to succeed!
では、1つ目のチャレンジは、こちら！
Now, the first challenge is this!
真剣　白羽取り　ならぬ　真剣　風返し取りーーーっ！
Catching a serious blow with bare hands... No, catching a serious gust of wind!
はい、ということでですね、オープニングでも歌っている通り、
Yes, so as I sang in the opening,
ちなみにふがしは空気ですってことで、こよはふがしが大好きです！
by the way, "fuga-shi" is air, so Koyori loves fuga-shi!
そんなふがしを今回作ってもらいました！
They made this fuga-shi for me this time!
じゃじゃじゃじゃじゃじゃーーーん！みおぼえのあるこのなんか、パーキングエリアでよく売れているお土産のこのふがし棒！
Tadaaaah! This familiar souvenir fuga-shi stick often sold at parking areas!
え、これを、ま、ふがしは空気なので当たっても痛くないやろってことで……
Eh, since fuga-shi is air, it won't hurt even if it hits me...
え、みんなにね、真剣のようにちょっとこよを狙ってもらおうと思います。
Eh, I'm going to have everyone try to target me as if it were a real sword.
お、お、やる気だね、女子くん！じゃ、ちょっと女子くん、あの「えいっ」てコメントで言ってもらっていいですか？「えいっ」てね。
Oh, oh, you're motivated, girl-kun! Then, girl-kun, could you say "Ei!" in the comments? Saying "Ei!".
よし、絶対受け止めてやるからよ。いくぞ！
Alright, I'll definitely catch it. Here we go!
ラウンドま…まだラウンド1って言ってないじゃん、女子くん！
Round ma... You haven't even said Round 1 yet, girl-kun!
ラウンド1って言おうとしたの、ねぇ痛いよ！空気のはずなのに！
I was trying to say Round 1, hey, it hurts! Even though it's supposed to be air!
ま、ま、ま、まぁいいです。女子くんはちょっと先走りしちゃうところもありますからね。
Well, well, well, it's fine. Girl-kun tends to get a little ahead of herself sometimes.
ラウンド2いくよ、ラウンド2！はい！ラウンド2、来い！
Going to Round 2, Round 2! Yes! Round 2, come!
うっ、ちゃっ！
Ugh, chah!
ね、早い！女子くん早い！あ、あ、あ、ちょっと、あ、野生、野生のがち、たぎってきた！
Hey, fast! Girl-kun is fast! Ah, ah, ah, wait, ah, my wild side is surging!
くうーーん！よしじゃあ3回目の勝負ということでこれラストチャンスでお願いします！えい、えい、よろしく！いくよ！
Kuuun! Alright, this is the 3rd match, so please, this is the last chance! Ei, ei, best regards! Here we go!
ぜっ、あ、お！ほっ！つか、つかまえたーーーっ！え、これ成功？
Ze, ah, o! Ho! Ca... caught it! Eh, is this a success?
成功？成功ですよね？やったーーー！女子くん、ちょっと最後手加減しちゃったんじゃないのーーーっ！？
Success? It's a success, right? Yay! Girl-kun, didn't you go a bit easy on me at the end?!
よった！え、じゃあもうこよ、アイドルとして一歩成長できた、ん？
Awesome! Eh, then Koyori has grown a step as an idol, hm?
あれ、でも2対1か。そっか。2対1だから、まぁなんかちゃんと勝ったって感じがせえへんか。
Huh, but it's 2 to 1. I see. It's 2 to 1, so I don't really feel like I won properly.
じゃ、じゃあ、とりあえず一応ね、成功した感はあるんだけど、2個目のチャレンジもいこうと思います！
Well, well, for now, I feel like I kind of succeeded, but I'm going to go for the second challenge too!
ばれたか、って言ってる。女子くんやっぱ手加減してくれるの優しいな！
"Did you find out?" she says. Girl-kun is so kind to go easy on me!
ではではでは、続いてのチャレンジはこちら！ぶら下がり1分チャレンジ！いえーーい！
Now, now, now, the next challenge is this! One-minute hanging challenge! Yay!
ということで、サバンナにぶら下がるものを立てようとしていますが
So, I'm trying to set up something to hang from in the savanna,
立ちません！
but it won't stand!
立ってて！立っててぶら下げるやつ立ってて！立たないよーー！立たないですーー！
Stand up! Stand up, hanging thing, stand up! It won't stand! It won't stand!
じゃあ、空気にぶら下がろうかな？あ、できたできた！きたきたきた！よかったよかった！
Well then, shall I hang from the air? Ah, it worked! It came! Thank goodness!
ということで、今のふがしを使って、
So, using that fuga-shi,
えーなんかちょっと鉄棒みたいなやつを作りました。
uh, I made something like a horizontal bar.
よかった、立ってくれるって。
I'm glad you agreed to stand.
で、これにね、ちょっとねぶら下がりたいなと思うんですけど、
So, I'd like to hang from this,
あの、やったこと、あまりないんですけど、多分楽勝だと思うんですよ。
um, I've never really done it before, but I think it'll be a total breeze.
なんていうか、あのぶら下がってるだけだとつまらないと思うんで、ちょっと視聴者くん、なんか質問とかあのコメント欄で書いてくれたらこより答えるので、
I feel like just hanging there would be boring, so viewers, if you could write some questions or comments in the chat, Koyori will answer them!
はい、じゃあやっていこうと思います！
Alright, let's do this!
せーの！
Ready, go!
スリーサイズは！スリーサイズは！スリーサイズ、スリーサイズ、本気ゅー！
My three sizes! My three sizes! Three sizes, three sizes, for real!
がんばれー！がんばれー！
Hang in there! Hang in there!
あー、野生の血が、か、わ、わ、わほー！わほほほ！
Ah, my feral instincts... Wa-ho! Wa-ho-ho-ho!
24秒！結構がんばったほうなんだけど、これはきつかった！
24 seconds! I think I did pretty well, but that was tough!
でも1個、1個スリーサイズ聞いてたの答えられたよ！
But I was able to answer one of the three-size questions I heard!
答え、答えれたけどこれは失敗ということは、
I was able to answer, but since this counts as a failure...
あれ？今なんか変なのエロいのつかなかったわ？あれ？やばい！
Huh? Didn't some weird thing just attach to me? Huh? Oh no!
野生に若干戻り始めているわ！
I'm starting to revert a bit to my wild state!
これは、これはどうしようもないわ！次の
There's nothing I can do about this! For the next
チャレンジに行くわ！次のチャレンジは
challenge, I'm going! The next challenge is...
バランスチャレンジわーん！
the balance challenge, woof!
おお！あ、これなの、これ遊び道具でてきた！
Oh! Ah, this, a toy came out!
わー！
Wah!
違うんや！違う、違う、野生じゃないわ！
That's not it! No, no, it's not wild!
と言うことで、こちらですね、こよが作ったバランスをこうぽよんぽよんと、やる事のできる、何言ってるかわかんなくなってきたわ！
So, this is a bouncy balance thing that Koyori made... I don't even know what I'm saying anymore!
バランスをね、あの保つことのできる爆弾です！イエーイ！
It's a bomb that lets you maintain your balance! Yay!
これルマの感想でもやってましたね、爆発ね。
We did this during Luma's review too, the explosion.
これに乗って10秒耐えることができたらチャレンジ成功ということで、やってみようと思いますわ！行くよ！
If you can ride this and last for 10 seconds, the challenge is a success, so I'm going to try it! Here we go!
いけるやろ！バランスボール！
I can do this! Balance ball!
さあ、行くぞ！せーの！
Here we go! Ready, go!
わあー！
Whoa!
あれ？もしや今こよ、あの人間じゃなくなってるから、
Huh? Wait, since Koyori isn't quite human right now,
あの四つ足のつもりでやった方がええんか？ということわ、四つ、ちょっと腹ばいでラストチャレンジやらせてくださいわ！
wouldn't it be better to do it on all fours? In that case, please let me do the final challenge on my stomach!
10秒、10秒こっちならいけるかもしれないわ！
10 seconds, maybe I can do it if I use this way!
いく、いくわ！いくわ！せーの！
Here I go! Here I go! Ready, go!
わーん！わあー！
Woof! Whoa!
ぷく、爆発じゃ、わっわっ！
Puku, an explosion, wa-wa!
あ、ちょっと戻ったわ！やばいもう日本語が喋れなくなってしまったわ！
Ah, I'm back a bit! Oh no, I can't speak Japanese properly anymore!
ということで、このままではアイドルを歌うとかそういうわけにもいかないので、
So, since I can't sing as an idol like this,
こんなときこそ前に開発しておいたあの薬を使いたいと思うわ！
I think I want to use that medicine I developed earlier for a time like this!
ええ、人間じゃないものになってしまったときに、人間に戻るための薬！いけよ！ワン！
Um, the medicine to return to human when you've become a non-human! Let's go! One!
あれ？椅子しかないはずなのに何かいっぱいあるわ！
Huh? There should only be chairs, but there are so many things here!
嗅覚が今冴え渡っているから、匂いで嗅げばわかるはずわ！
My sense of smell is super sharp right now, so if I sniff them, I should know!
くンくン、これはなんか泥臭い匂いがするわ！こっちは？
Sniff, sniff... This has a muddy smell! What about this?
これはなんかフレッシュで、オレンジみたいな香りがするわ！次！
This smells fresh, like oranges! Next!
あ、これ甘くて、色も紫色だし可愛い香りがするわ！次！
Ah, this is sweet, purple, and has a cute scent! Next!
あ、美味しそう！飲もうかなと思ったら急に出てきたんだけど。
Ah, looks delicious! I thought about drinking it, but it just suddenly appeared.
びっくりさせるのはってことで、
To surprise you all...
じゃあ、これはね、今宵の試検管が正解やろ！
Well, this must be Koyori's correct test tube!
じゃ、さ、おいしょ！
So, ready, heave-ho!
行くわよ、むわん！
Here I go, muwan!
あ、よいしょ、しょ、しょ、しょ、しょ...
Ah, heave-ho, heave-ho...
はぁはぁはぁ en:
Haah, haah, haah...
元に、戻れましたー！
I made it back!
はい、アイドルに戻ってくることができました！みんな、ただいま！
Yes, I managed to return as an idol! Everyone, I'm back!
息切れるな
I'm running out of breath.
息切れるとる！
I am completely out of breath!
ということで、これはね、今宵のアイドルチャレンジ
So, this was Koyori's Idol Challenge!
ジップハトリで1回成功したけど、なんか、成功感があんまない、ないですかね？
I succeeded once with the zipline, but... don't you feel like it lacks a sense of accomplishment?
ね、成功したってことで
Well, considering it a success,
いいよね？助手君。い、いいよね？
it's fine, right, Assistant? Is it? It's fine, right?
不正じゃないよ？
It's not cheating, you know?
いいよね？オッケー？
It's fine, right? Okay?
あ、助手君、やっぱり優しい！ありがとう、いいよ、ありがとう！
Ah, Assistant, you're so kind after all! Thank you, that's good, thank you!
じゃあ、ちゃんとアイドルとして成長できたってことで、ラボに戻って、あの曲を歌いたいと思います！戻るよ！さあ、飛行機に乗るぞー！
So, since I've grown properly as an idol, I'd like to return to the lab and sing that song! Returning! Now, time to board the plane!
ほら、粉雪だよ、せーの、こ、こ、粉雪です！
Look, it's powdered snow! Ready, p-p-powdered snow!
はい、ハチダグ、今宵設計チャレンジだ！
Yes, Hatchi-dog, Koyori's design challenge!
オッケー！今宵はすの、すの、すのーです！はい、やったー！
Okay! Tonight is s-s-snow! Yes, yay!
小雪スケッチ、しぇ、しぇ、はい、せーの！はい、はい、はい！
Koyuki sketch, she-she, yes, ready! Yes, yes, yes!
研究熱心、試検管！はい、はい、はい、はい、はい！
Passionate researcher, test tube! Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes!
可愛い小雪の試検管！はい、はい、はい、はい！
Cute Koyuki's test tube! Yes, yes, yes, yes!
今宵の助手君は寝る！はい、はい、はい、はい、はい、すのー、せろぷ！
Tonight's Assistant sleeps! Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, snow, syrup!
はい、はい、はい、はい、すのー、るんぴーな！はい、はい、はい、はい、そーまんなんでね、見えた！
Yes, yes, yes, yes, snow, rumpīna! Yes, yes, yes, yes, it's Soma, so I saw it!
はい、はい、はい、はい、でもいいです、せや！はい、はい、はい、はい、オッケー！
Yes, yes, yes, yes, but it's fine, seya! Yes, yes, yes, yes, okay!
こゆ、粉雪です！そー、はい、せーの、こ、こ、粉雪です！
Koy- powdered snow! So, yes, ready, p-p-powdered snow!
やったー！集まったー！マヨネーズは飲み物です！ちなみに、ぶっちゃけ炭酸です！
Yay! Gathered! Mayonnaise is a drink! By the way, honestly, it's carbonated!
はい、お肉、試検管、製造うどんは常備しています！そうですか？やったー！正面顔よくいい！
Yes, meat, test tube, manufacturing udon is always stocked! Is that so? Yay! Front face is good!
はい、はい、はい、きゅ、きゅ、きゅ、きゅ、い！
Yes, yes, yes, kyu, kyu, kyu, kyu, i!
コックだの、コック、や、や、や、い！
Cook and cook, ya, ya, ya, i!
次の君は、小雪のつくる！はい、はい、はい、はい！
Next, you are Koyuki's creation! Yes, yes, yes, yes!
どうしようかな？むいむい、むいむい、はい、はい、はい、はい、おやー、いきませんね！
What should I do? Mui-mui, mui-mui, yes, yes, yes, yes, oh dear, it's no good!
はい、はい、はい、はい、お餅にしましょう！そう！
Yes, yes, yes, yes, let's make it rice cakes! Yes!
はい、はい、はい、はい、おーる、おーる、おーる、すの、おーる、すの、い、イエス！はい、はい、はい、おーる、すのー、ふふふ！
Yes, yes, yes, yes, all, all, all, snow, all, snow, i, yes! Yes, yes, yes, all, snow, haha!
それでは、勇気が出たときに歌うと言っていた、あの曲！ホロライブの全体曲、聞いてください！
Now then, please listen to that song I said I'd sing when I got the courage! Hololive's group song!
シャイニースマイリーストーリー！
Shiny Smily Story!
同じ未来を見ていたい
Wanting to see the same future,
あの夢手にしたい
wanting to hold that dream in my hands.
それぞれ違ったココロで走れGO
With each of our different hearts, run, go!
どこを見ても真っ暗な場所に芽生えてた
Sprouting even in a pitch-black place wherever I looked,
ほんの小さな希望にこの瞳奪われた
my eyes were stolen by a tiny hope.
不安で揺れる心を上手くチューニングして
Tuning my trembling heart of anxiety smoothly,
ほんの小さな勇気を振り絞っていたよ
I mustered up a tiny bit of courage.
諦めの文字デリートして進む
Deleting the word "give up," I move forward.
苦しいときも、もう私はひとりじゃないから
Even in hard times, I'm no longer alone,
だからもっと夢追いかけたい ワクワク止まらない
so I want to chase my dreams even more, excitement won't stop!
想像超えていく世界見せてあげる
I'll show you a world surpassing imagination,
アクセスしてみたい 後悔なんてそうさせない
I want to access it, and I won't let you have any regrets!
それぞれ違ったココロで
With each of our different hearts,
走れGO
run, go!
仮想の空に輝く眩しい想いは
The dazzling feelings shining in the virtual sky
見たことのない光を リアルに届けるよ
Delivering an unseen light to reality!
いつも聞こえるエールは ここにキャプチャーして
Capturing all the cheers I always hear right here,
また新しい光を 探したくなるよ
It makes me want to search for brand new lights!
君の笑顔は保存して進む
I'll save your smile as I move forward,
悲しいときに見返すよ
To look back on when I feel sad,
力が湧くから
Because it fills me with strength!
胸を張って夢追いかけたい
Standing proud, I want to chase my dreams,
奇跡の物語(ストーリー) 一緒に作ろう
Creating a miraculous story together!
終わらない夢を 誰一人欠かせない
An endless dream where no one can be left behind,
愛が舞ったこの世界
In this world where love dances around.
それぞれ違ったココロで 彩れ
Let's color it with our unique hearts!
悲しいときも 寂しいときも
Even when I'm sad or lonely,
信じ合えるものがある
There's something we can believe in together.
忘れずにこの鼓動鳴らし続けたい
I want to keep this heartbeat ringing without forgetting,
終わらない世界に溢れ出すよ
Overflowing into an endless world,
笑顔達
All our smiles!
憧れの舞台立ちたい 私らしく輝きたい
I want to stand on the stage of my dreams and shine as myself,
時に涙して また笑い合いたい
Shedding tears at times, and laughing together again.
同じ未来を見たい あの夢手にしたい
I want to see the same future and hold that dream in my hands,
踏み出そう 奇跡の一歩を
Taking a miraculous first step forward!
息切らして夢追いかけたい
Gasping for breath, I want to chase my dreams,
ワクワク止まらない
With excitement that won't stop!
想像を超えてく 世界見せてあげる
I'll show you a world that goes beyond imagination,
アクセスしてみてない? 後悔なんてここにない
Won't you try accessing it? There's no room for regrets here!
それぞれ違ったココロで 作る WORLD
Building a world with our unique hearts!
はぁい！
Hii!
やっと耐えた！サインにスマイリスーパーストーリーでした！
I finally survived! That was "Shiny Smily Story"!
みんな届いたかな！
Did it reach everyone?
読むむっちゃね、ちょっと考え深くなっちゃって
Reading all that made me get a bit emotional,
自分の中でちょっと今クライマックスなんだけども、
And I feel like it's the climax inside me right now, but...
まだまだ終わらないんだよ！
It's still not over yet!
なんと、重大告知ありってサミニールに書いてありましたからね！
As written in the thumbnail, there's a major announcement!
え、ここでちょっとお知らせです！
Um, here is a little notice!
まずは！ホロックスがどんどん3D化されておりますが、
First off! HoloX members are gradually getting 3D models,
次に3Dになるのは……こいつだー！
and the next one to get 3D is... this person!
鷹嶺ルイ 3Dお披露目 6月21日 火曜日 20:00~
[Takane Lui 3D Reveal - June 21 (Tue) 20:00~]
次はホロックスの頭脳幹部、鷹嶺ルイが
Next is HoloX's brain and executive, Takane Lui,
6月21日火曜日20時から！3Dお披露目配信を行います！
on June 21st at 20:00! She'll have her 3D reveal stream!
みんな！一緒に見に行こね！
Everyone! Let's go watch it together!
メンバーシップ限定 打ち上げ撮影会 おうち3D
[Membership-only Afterparty Photoshoot - Home 3D]
メンバーシップ限定で本日23時から配信を行うのですが、
We'll have a membership-only stream tonight from 23:00,
さっそくおうち3Dを使って、3Dで配信をしようと思っております！
and I'm planning to use the home 3D setup for a 3D stream!
そして！次が、重大告知だー！ででーん！
And then! Next is the major announcement! Ta-da!
WAO!! Hakui Koyori 1st Original Song
[WAO!! - Hakui Koyori 1st Original Song]
ということで、なんと！博衣こより初めてのオリジナル曲を作りました！いぇーい！
So, amazingly, I've created my very first original song!
こちらのオリジナル曲、DECO*27さんに作っていただいた、こよりらしさがいっぱい詰まった曲となっております！
This song was made by DECO*27-san, packed with all things Koyori!
さらにですね、こちら、このあと6月16日の24時、6月17日の0時になった瞬間にですね、販売リリースされます！
And it releases the moment June 16th turns to June 17th at 0:00!
ぜひ買ってください！よろしくお願いします！
Please buy it! Thank you so much!
さらに、WAO!!のMV、このお披露目配信が終わったあと、21時5分ぐらいからプレミア公開を行います！
Furthermore, the MV for "WAO!!" premieres at 21:05 after this stream!
是非ともMVもぜひ見てってください
Please definitely check out the MV too!
超可愛く仕上がっておりますので、MVも見てね、お願いします！
It turned out super cute, so please watch the MV too!
そしてここで
And now, right here...
歌って踊っちゃいます！シャキーン！
I'm going to sing and dance! Ta-da!
えーわおをねみんなにお届けするのはやっぱこのお披露目の場で初めてお届けしたいなと思ったので
I wanted to deliver "WAO!!" to everyone for the very first time right here at my 3D debut,
リコニーナさんがね一生懸命もこよるをいっぱい詰めてくださっためっちゃ可愛いくてかっこいい曲なので
and since Liconi-na worked so hard to pack it full of Koyori, making it super cute and cool,
ここで踊りもめっちゃね頑張って、もうこれ一番頑張ってるぐらい頑張っているので
I'm working super hard on the dance—probably harder than on anything else—
ぜひ最後まで見て聞いていってくれたら嬉しいです。
so I'd be so happy if you watched and listened all the way to the end!
それでは本日最後の曲、白衣こより初めてのオリジナル曲、聞いてください、わおー！
Now, for the final song today, my very first original song as Hakui Koyori—please enjoy "WAO!!"
もうきみのところチクっとしちゃえ
Let's give you a little prick right now~
わおーん！
Wao-n!
全然無理をもっちゃうし
I always take on way too much,
だってだって不安になるし
'cause I get so anxious, you know.
全然嘘つけないし
I totally can't lie,
だってだってバカ真っ直ぐだし
'cause I'm just ridiculously straightforward.
目指すキラキラもっとぼく次第だ
The sparkle I'm aiming for depends more on me!
ピター？ギブアップなんて言わないんだから
Pita? There's no way I'm saying "give up"!
じっとしてらんないし
I can't stay still,
だってだって動いちゃう脚
'cause my legs just want to move!
ワン！ワン！ステップアップ ちょっとずつ進めば 夢の式解けちゃうの
One! Two! Step up, advancing bit by bit will solve the formula of our dreams!
なりたいぼくを きみが好きなぼくを ちゃんとあまりなく見せたいの
The me I want to be, the me you love—I want to show you without holding anything back!
あっちゃっちゃ びっくりするほどできないじゃん 間違って悩んでばっかりじゃん
Oopsie-daisy, I'm shockingly bad at this, always making mistakes and worrying!
けどきみに見つけてほしくて ぼくはきみを迎えに行くんだ 出会えたならハッピー
But I want you to find me, so I'm going out to meet you—meeting you makes me happy!
わーお！叫んじゃえ 泣いて鳴いて愛して尻尾振って
Wao! Shout it out, crying, calling out, loving, wagging my tail!
わーお！叫んじゃえ
Wao! Shout it out!
だめなぼくをどうか覚えていて
Please remember this useless me somehow!
もうきみのところチクっとしちゃえ
Let's give you a little prick right now~
もうどうしようとかたまに思って沈んだり
Sometimes I wonder what to do and get all gloomy,
案外いけるかもふわり浮かんじゃって元通り
but then float up thinking "hey, maybe I'm fine" and bounce right back.
ベッタリがやめられない おすわりってそれなんだっけ？
I can't stop being clingy—wait, what was "sit" again?
うっかりが止められない また歩いて壁に当たるの
I keep slipping up and running into walls again!
ワン！ワン！ステップアップ 死んだふりするのやめて はい、こっちおいで
One! Two! Step up, stop playing dead, come over here!
欲しがるきみと上げすぎのぼくで もっといける気がしています
With you wanting more and me giving too much, I feel like we can go even further!
あっちゃっちゃ びっくりするほどできないじゃん 間違って悩んでばっかりじゃん
Oopsie-daisy, I'm shockingly bad at this, always making mistakes and worrying!
けどきみに見つけてほしくて ぼくはきみを迎えに行くんだ 出会えたならハッピー
But I want you to find me, so I'm going out to meet you—meeting you makes me happy!
わーお！叫んじゃえ やっぱりひとりじゃだめだけど 集まってバカしてわおっちゃえば
Wao! Shout it out, being alone is no good, but if we get together and act silly,
ほら、いつでも言える「おかえり」 ぼくはきみに伝えたいんだ 大いなるハッピー
look, we can always say "Welcome back"—I want to tell you about this grand happiness!
わーお！叫んじゃえ 泣いて鳴いて愛して尻尾振って わーお！叫んじゃえ
Wao! Shout it out, crying, calling out, loving, wagging my tail! Wao! Shout it out!
だめなぼくをどうか覚えていて
Please remember this useless me somehow!
目指すキラキラもっとぼく次第だ ピター？ギブアップなんて言わないんだ
The sparkle I'm aiming for depends more on me! Pita? There's no way I'm saying "give up"!
加速メラーメラでぶっちぎり時代だ 駆け抜けろ希望へ大暴走
It's an era of blazing acceleration, running wild toward hope!
きみのところチクっとしちゃって いいじゃんハッピージャン
Pricking your heart—isn't that just happy-chan?
はーい！というわけで、わお、どうだったかな？最後だったりそう。あっつーい！
Phew! So, how was "WAO!!"? It was the last song, right? Phew, it's hot!
ということで、この後ですね、えーWAOのMV、すぐ21時5分から、えープレミア公開させていただくので、それも見ていってください！
So right after this, the MV for "WAO!!" will premiere at 21:05, so please go check that out too!
そして、えー21時になったら、えー公開されます、リリースされますので、それも是非是非おめでとうの気持ちを手に取って、ください！
And at 21:00 it will be released, so please grab it with your congratulatory feelings!
わおー！っていっぱい歌ってね、よろしく！
Sing "WAO!!" a bunch, okay!
そして3Dお披露目配信、1時間おとに見てくれて、ありがとう！
And thank you so much for watching my 3D debut stream for a whole hour!
えー、これから3Dになってできることいっぱい増えて、いろんなことやっていきたいと思っているので、応援これからもよろしくね！
Now that I'm in 3D, there are so many more things I can do and want to try, so please keep supporting me!
助手くん、みんな、大好きだぞー！ありがとう！
Assistant-kun, everyone, I love you all so much! Thank you!
博衣こより 3D お披露目 重大告知アリ!!
[Hakui Koyori 3D Debut - Major Announcement!]